tahometer.com 2017-06-06

# Privacy Policy of Tahometer

Date of last revision: March 12, 2010.

Defined Terms. "Us," "we," "our," "Service" and "Tahometer" mean the same. "Information" and "content" are used more generally and interchangeably here:

We want to earn your trust by being transparent about how Tahometer works. You should read this policy in its entirety, but should pay particular attention to these three highlights:

  * Tahometer is designed to make it easy for you to share your activity information with anyone you want. You decide how much information you feel comfortable sharing on Tahometer and you control how it is distributed through your privacy settings. You should review the shared data before sharing and consider your settings whenever you share information.
  * Tahometer is not just a website. It is also a standalone service for tracking your activity and uploading this information to tahometer service websites. You can control how you share information through your tahometer agent application settings.
  * In future we plan to have ability make certain categories of information such as your name, profile, skills, geographic region and total statistic available to everyone. You will have ability, however, limit the ability of others to see and find this information through search using your search privacy settings. This information **will not be** accessible to others by default.

## Information We Receive

### Information you provide to us:

Personal information. When you sign up as Tahometer user you provide us with your name, email, and information about your time zone. During the service usage we will give you the opportunity to provide additional information.

Content. One of the primary reasons people use Tahometer is to share their working activity content with others.

Information we collect when you interact with Tahometer:

Site activity information. We keep track of the actions you take on Tahometer, such as website navigation, versions of browser and Tahometer Agent, creating or editing items, or authorizing an application.

When you access Tahometer from a Tahometer Agent, we may collect information received from that Agent application, and your IP address, as well as the list of service functions you are using.

Cookie Information. We use "cookies" (small pieces of data we store for an extended period of time on your computer) to make Tahometer easier to use, and to protect both you and Tahometer. For example, we use them to store your login ID (but never your password) to make it easier for you to login whenever you come back to Tahometer. We also use them to confirm that you are logged into Tahometer, and to know when you are interacting with Tahometer Agent application and websites. You can remove or block cookies using the settings in your browser, but in some cases that may impact your ability to use Tahometer.

### Information we receive from third parties:

We do not own all applications or services that use Tahometer for time tracking. We refer to them as “Tahometer-enhanced” applications and websites because they use our Platform to provide you with addition features. Whenever you authorize a Tahometer-enhanced application or website, we can receive information from them, including information about actions you take. In some cases, in order to personalize the process of connecting, we may receive a limited amount of information even before you authorize the application or website.

Information from other websites. We may institute programs with partners and other websites in which they share information with us.

### Information You Share With Third Parties

We take steps to ensure that others use information that you share on Tahometer in a manner consistent with your privacy settings, but we cannot guarantee that they will follow our rules. Read the following section to learn more about how you can protect yourself when you share information with third parties.

Sharing information on Tahometer. We designed our privacy settings to enable you to control how you share your information on Tahometer. You should review the default privacy settings to make sure they reflect your preferences. Here are some specific things to remember:

  * You can control the visibility of most of the information you share on Tahometer through the settings you select.
  * Certain types of communications that you send to other users cannot be removed, such as messages.
  * When you comment on another user’s activity, that information will be subject to the other user’s privacy settings.
  * You can use your privacy settings to limit which of your information is available to “everyone”.

You should always review the policies of third party applications and websites to make sure you are comfortable with the ways in which they use information you share with them. We do not guarantee that they will follow our rules. If you find an application or website that violates our rules, you should report the violation to us on this help page and we will take action as necessary.

Exporting Information. You (and those you make your information available to) may use tools, or copy and paste functions, to capture and export information from Tahometer, including your information and information about you.

Links. When you click on links on Tahometer you may leave our site. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of other sites, and we encourage you to read their privacy statements.

## How We Use Your Information

We use the information we collect to try to provide a safe, efficient, and customized experience. Here are some of the details on how we do that:

To manage the service. We use the information we collect to provide our services and features to you, to measure and improve those services and features, and to provide you with customer support. We use the information to prevent potentially illegal activities. We also use a variety of technological systems to detect and address anomalous activity. These efforts may on occasion result in a temporary or permanent suspension or termination of some functions, some users or user locations.

To contact you. We may contact you with service-related announcements from time to time. You may opt out of all communications except essential updates on your account notifications page. We may include content you see on Tahometer in the emails we send to you.

Downloadable Software. Certain downloadable software applications that we offer, such as our Tahometer Agent, transmit data to us. We may not make a formal disclosure if we believe our collection of and use of the information is the obvious purpose of the application, such as the fact that we receive desktop screenshots, titles of active windows, numbers of mouse clicks and pressed keys for certain period of time. If we believe it is not obvious that we are collecting or using such information, we will make a disclosure to you the first time you provide the information to us so that you can decide whether you want to use that feature.

## How We Share Information

Tahometer is about sharing information with others while providing you with privacy settings that you can use to restrict other users from accessing your information. We share your information with third parties when we believe the sharing is permitted by you, reasonably necessary to offer our services, or when legally required to do so. For example:

When you make a payment. When you enter into transactions with others or make payments on Tahometer, we will only share transaction information with those third parties necessary to complete the transaction and will require those third parties to agree to respect the privacy of your information.

To help improve or promote our service. Sometimes we share aggregated information with third parties to help improve or promote our service. But we only do so in such a way that no individual user can be identified or linked to any specific action or information.

To provide you with services. We may provide information to service providers that help us bring you the services we offer. For example, we may use third parties to help host our website, send out email updates about Tahometer, process payments. These service providers may have access to your personal information for use for a limited time, but when this occurs we implement reasonable contractual and technical protections to limit their use of that information to helping us provide the service.

To offer joint services. We may provide services jointly with other companies. If you use these services, we may share your information to facilitate that service. However, we will identify the partner and present the joint service provider’s privacy policy to you before you use that service.

To respond to legal requests and prevent harm. We may disclose information pursuant to subpoenas, court orders, or other requests (including criminal and civil matters)

Transfer in the Event of Sale or Change of Control. If the ownership of all or substantially all of our business changes, we may transfer your information to the new owner so that the service can continue to operate. In such a case, your information would remain subject to the promises made in any pre-existing Privacy Policy.

Deactivating or deleting your account. If you want to stop using your account you may deactivate it or delete it. When you deactivate an account, no user will be able to see it, but it will not be deleted. We save your profile information in case you later decide to reactivate your account. Many users deactivate their accounts for temporary reasons and in doing so are asking us to maintain their information until they return to Tahometer. You will still have the ability to reactivate your account and restore your profile in its entirety. When you delete an account, it is permanently deleted. You should only delete your account if you are certain you never want to reactivate it. You may deactivate your account on your account settings page or delete your account on this help page.

Limitations on removal. Even after you remove information from your profile or delete your account, copies of that information may remain viewable elsewhere to the extent it has been shared with others, it was otherwise distributed pursuant to your privacy settings, or it was copied or stored by other users. However, your name will no longer be associated with that information on Tahometer. (For example, if you post something to another user’s profile, and then you delete your account, that post may remain, but be attributed to an “Anonymous Tahometer User.”) Additionally, we may retain certain information to prevent identity theft and other misconduct even if deletion has been requested.

Backup copies. Removed and deleted information may persist in backup copies for up to 90 days, but will not be available to others.

## How We Protect Information

We do our best to keep your information secure, but we need your help.

Steps we take to keep your information secure. We keep your account information on a secured server behind a firewall. When you enter sensitive information (such as credit card numbers and passwords), we encrypt that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL). We also use automated and social measures to enhance security, such as analyzing account behavior for fraudulent or otherwise anomalous behavior, may limit use of site features in response to possible signs of abuse, may remove inappropriate content or links to illegal content, and may suspend or disable accounts.

Risks inherent in sharing information. Although we allow you to set privacy options that limit access to your information, please be aware that no security measures are perfect or impenetrable. We cannot control the actions of other users with whom you share your information. We cannot guarantee that only authorized persons will view your information. We cannot ensure that information you share on Tahometer will not become publicly available. We are not responsible for third party circumvention of any privacy settings or security measures on Tahometer. You can reduce these risks by using common sense security practices such as choosing a strong password, using different passwords for different services, and using up to date antivirus software.

Report Violations. You should report any security violations to us on using feedback link at the left of main page.

## Other Terms

Changes. We may change this Privacy Policy pursuant. Unless stated otherwise, our current privacy policy applies to all information that we have about you and your account. If we make changes to this Privacy Policy we will notify you by publication here.

Consent to Collection and Processing in the United States. By using Tahometer, you consent to having your personal data transferred to and processed in the United States.

Defined Terms. "Us," "we," "our," "Service" and "Tahometer" mean the same. “Information” and “content” are used more generally and interchangeably here.
